Finding Aid for Robert R. McMath Papers 1916-1962
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert R. McMath Papers 1916-1962
McMath, Robert R. (Robert Raynolds), 1891-1962.
Detroit, Michigan industrialist and director of the McMath-Hulbert Observatory of University of Michigan (located on Lake Angelus near Pontiac, Oakland County, Michigan.). Correspondence concerning astronomy, particularly celestial photography, and the development of the McMath Observatory, financial records, plans for telescope equipment, and printed materials.
851801 Aa 2
10 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection came to the library in different accessions from different donors. Robert McMath (donor no. 2623 ) donated some materials in 1949. The bulk of the collection came from the U-M astronomy department (donor no. 1435 ) in 1949 and 1962. In 1978, Orren Mohler (donor no. 4765 ) acting for the astronomy department donated McMath's American Astronomical Society papers.
The collection is open for research.
The time has vanished when a man such as Isaac Newton could cultivate a knowledge of natural philosophy outside a formal institutional setting while, at the same time, restructuring man's understanding of the cosmos. For one thing, the specialization of knowledge has virtually extinguished the possibility of such an enterprise; for another, scientific investigation has been transformed from a primarily individual matter into one which is administered, financed and conceived within large institutions, such as the University of Michigan. This transformation from, what one author has called, "Little Science" to "Big Science" has been so complete that, in examining the past of history of science, it is apparent that a profound change has occurred in the etymology of the word "science."
Against this background the career of Robert R. McMath acquires both meaning and fascination. For he was probably one of few men to convert a personal hobby (astronomy) into a productive scientific career. McMath's background in engineering is very much reflected through his interests in, what he was fond of calling, "things astronomical." His innovations tend to be technical, rather than conceptual. Celestial photography was the area with which he was most concerned; and, consequently, many of the papers deal with motion picture techniques, the development of new instruments for studying and photographing spectra (e.g. spectrohelio-kinsmatograph, photometer), and necessary adaptations in the telescope. In addition to its value as a source in the history of astronomy, the collection may also be used profitably to study the financial and structural growth of a scientific organization; and, of course, the relationship of the University and the government to scientific endeavor.
Robert R. McMath was born May 11, 1891 in Detroit, Michigan. He graduated with a degree in civil engineering from the University of Michigan in 1913, then worked for his father's company and another firm before entering the army air service in 1917. After the war he became general manager of the Biltmore Forest Estates Company in North Carolina. He then returned to Detroit as assistant manager of the Motors Metal Manufacturing Co. He worked for this company (and the firms that merged from it) for the next forty years in a succession of responsible positions: general manager, president, and chairman of the board.
McMath's passion was astronomy which he shared with his father and with Detroit banker and judge Henry S. Hulbert. He was supportive of the work of astronomers at the University of Michigan and was able to make many gifts to his alma mater. On his property near Lake Angelus in Oakland County, the McMaths (father and son) and Judge Hulbert had been planning and building a telescope. In 1931, the property was deeded to the University of Michigan. Among the equipment designed and built at Lake Angelus were a 70-foot tower telescope, a 24-inch reflecting telescope, and a 50-foot solar tower. From 1939 to 1961, McMath was director of the McMath-Hulbert Observatory; and from 1945 to 1960, he was named professor of solar physics and astronomy at the University of Michigan.
McMath was the recipient of many awards and honors. He was a member of the American Association for Advancement of Science, the American Philosophical Society, the American Astronomical Society, and the Royal Astronomical Society. In addition, he was director of Cranbrook School (1929-1946), and a trustee of the Cranbrook Institute of Science (chairman, 1946-1950). He died January 2, 1962.
The Robert R. McMath papers consist primarily of correspondence concerning astronomy, particularly celestial photography, and the development of the McMath-Hulbert Observatory of the University of Michigan, financial records, plans for telescope equipment, and printed materials. Correspondents include some leading astronomers of the day but the bulk is with his collaborators in construction and operation of the Observatory and with the Heber D. Curtis, chair of the University of Michigan Astronomy Department and university president Alexander Ruthven. Writings include articles by McMath about the equipment and operation of the observatory and reports on specific astronomical observations made there. The papers have been arranged into the following series: Biographical; Correspondence; Miscellaneous; Organizational Affiliations; Writings; McMath-Hulbert Observatory, Lake Angelus; and Research and topical files.
Subjects:
Astronomy--Michigan.; Detroit (Mich.); McMath, Robert R. (Robert Raynolds), 1891-1962.; McMath-Hulbert Observatory (University of Michigan); National Science Foundation (U.S.); Pontiac (Mich.); University of Michigan. Dept. of Astronomy.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Observatory.
Contributors:
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.; Adams, Walter Sydney, 1876-1956.; Adel, Arthur, 1908-1994; Allen, Irwin, 1916-1991; Avila Camacho, Manuel, 1897-1955.; Barker, Ernest F. (Ernest Franklin), 1886-1970; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Burns, Kevin, 1881-1958.; Burr, George L. (George Lindsley), 1889-1971; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974.; Cisler, Walker L. (Walker Lee), 1897-1994; Cranbrook Institute of Science.; Cranbrook School (Bloomfield Hills, Mich.); Curtis, Heber Doust, 1872-1942.; Curtiss, Ralph Hamilton, 1880-1929.; Dale, Albert Ennis, 1890-1954.; Davison, Frederick Trubee, 1896-1974; Dodson, Helen Walter, 1905-; Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1893-1969.; Dunham, Theodore J., 1897-; Eckart, Carl, 1902-1973; Edmondson, Frank K. (Frank Kelly), 1912-; Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.; Fecker, J. W.; Fisher, Clyde, 1878-1949.; Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1889-1970.; Gilmore, William Steele, 1884-; Goldberg, Leo.; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966.; Grosvenor, Melville Bell, 1901-1982.; Heyns, Roger W. (Roger William), 1918-1995; Hulbert, Henry Schoolcraft, 1869-1959.; Johnson, Nelson C.; Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956.; Keller, Kaufman Thuma, 1885-1966.; Kellogg, Remington, 1893-; Keniston, Hayward, b. 1883.; Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-1973; Learer, F. H.; McClure, Roy Donaldson, 1882-1951.; McDowell, C. S.; McGregor, Tracy William, 1869-1936.; McMath, Francis Charles, 1867-1938.; Malesky, George.; Menzel, Donald H. (Donald Howard), 1901-1976; Merrill, Paul W. (Paul Willard), 1887-1961.; Mohler, Orren, 1908-; Nicholson, Seth B. (Seth Barnes), 1891-1963; Norton, William J. (William John), 1883-1975.; Odegaard, Charles E.; Ormondroyd, J. (Jesse), 1897-; Petrie, Robert Methven, 1906-; Pettit, Edison, 1889-1962; Pyke, Alfred Joseph, 1880-; Quarles, Donald Aubrey, 1894-1959.; Reynolds, Harrison G.; Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1899-; Russell, Henry Norris, 1877-1957.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sass, Samuel, 1915-; Sawyer, H. E.; Schauer, Charles Hawver, 1912-; Schriever, Bernard A.; Scripps, William Edmund, 1882-1952.; Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972.; Shirley, Joseph W.; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.; Stebbins, Joel, 1878-1966; Stetson, Harlan True, 1885-1964.; Stone, Julius Frederick, 1855-1947.; Struve, Otto, 1897-1963.; Tapping, Theodore Hawley, 1889-1969.; Waterman, Alan Tower, 1892-1967; Whipple, Fred L. (Fred Lawrence), 1906-2004; White, Alfred H. (Alfred Holmes), b. 1873.; Wilson, Charles Erwin, 1890-1961.; Yoakum, Clarence Stone, 1879-1945.
- Biographical
  - Vitae, dossiers, bibliography, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series is organized annually, 1928-1962. The volume begins to increase about 1932, reaches a peak period from 1937 to 1942, and drops off significantly in the postwar years, particularly after 1950. Appended to this finding aid is an extensive index to McMath's correspondents. Most of his correspondents relates to astronomy, his observatory, and his interaction with the University of Michigan. What little McMath reveals of his views on politics and personal matters will probably be found in his correspondence with Julius F. Stone. Aside from his letters to his father, Francis McMath, and the other collaborator on the observatory, Judge Henry S. Hulbert, McMath's major correspondent is astronomy department chairman Heber D. Curtis.
  - Undated, 1916-1935, 59 folders (Box 1)
  - 1936-1938, 41 folders (Box 2)
  - 1939-May 1941, 45 folders (Box 3)
  - June 1941-1946, 61 folders (Box 4)
  - 1947-1959, 50 folders (Box 5)
  - 1960-1962, 9 folders (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - 1930-1940, 28 folders (Box 7)
  - 1941-1962, 27 folders (Box 7)
- Organizational Affiliations
  - Cranbrook Institute of Science
    - Founding document (Box 7)
    - Interview between McMath and Robert T. Hatt concerning early history of the Cranbrook Institute of Science 1956 (Box 7)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - 1940, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - 1941, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - 1942, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - 1943, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1944 (Box 7)
    - 1945 (Box 7)
    - 1955 (Box 7)
      dedication of Robert R. McMath Planetarium
  - Mathematical, Physical, and Engineering Sciences Division of National Science Foundation
    - 1952-1954 (Box 8)
    - March 1955 (Box 8)
    - October 1955, 2 volumes; 1 folders (Box 8)
    - March 1956, 1 volumes; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - October 1956, 3 volumes; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1957, 1 volumes; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - American Astronomical Society
    - 1942-1951 (Box 9)
    - 1952 (Box 9)
    - January-June 1953 (Box 9)
    - July-December 1953 (Box 9)
    - January-June 1954 (Box 9)
    - July-December 1954 (Box 9)
    - January-June 1955 (Box 9)
    - July-December 1955 (Box 9)
    - January-June 1956 (Box 9)
    - July-December 1956 (Box 9)
    - 1957 (Box 9)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 9)
  - Other Organizations
    - Interamerican Astrophysics Congress 1942 (Box 9)
    - International Astronomical Union 1955 (Box 9)
    - National Academy of Science meeting 1959 (Box 9)
    - National Radio Astronomy Observatory 1956 (Box 9)
- Writings
  - "Prominences of the Active and Sunspot Types Compared," by Robert McMath and Edison Pettit 1937 (Box 9)
  - "The Tower Telescope of the McMath-Hulbert Observatory," by Robert McMath (Box 9)
  - "Recent Studies in Solar Phenomena" by Robert McMath, and notes concerning solar prominence studies 1938 (Box 9)
  - "A Review of Lake Angelus Tower Telescope Motion Picture Records," by Robert McMath and Harold Sawyer 1938 (Box 9)
  - "A Review of Lake Angelus Prominence Observations," by Robert McMath and Harold Sawyer 1939 (Box 9)
  - "The Measurement of Space Motions of Solar Prominences" by Robert McMath 1941 (Box 9)
- McMath-Hulbert Observatory, Lake Angelus
  - History 1959 (Box 9)
  - Financial Correspondence and Statements 1932-1940, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous surveys of McMath's Lake Angelus estate (Box 9)
  - Miscellanea concerning 10 1/2 inch telescope 1930-1933 (Box 9)
  - Notes on the history of McMath-Hulbert Observatory (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
- Research and topical files
  - Record of solar prominences 1938-1939 (Box 9)
  - Solar prominences papers (Box 9)
  - Study of solar prominence 1950 (Box 9)
  - Early solar tower telescope undated, 1937-1941, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Solar tower telescopes 1951 (Box 9)
  - Solar eclipse of August 31, 1932 (Box 10)
    (include logbook)
  - Photometer 1947 (Box 10)
  - 24 inch telescope construction (Box 10)
  - 10 1/2 inch telescope, small tower coelostat, 24 inch telescope (Box 10)
  - Auxiliary coelostat and spectrohelio radialgraph (Box 10)
  - Telescopes 1930-1934, undated, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Telescope construction, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Mt. Wilson spectrohelioscope (Box 10)
  - Observatory electrical circuits, notes concerning (Box 10)
  - Observatory "Dome Instructions" 1930-1935 (Box 10)
  - Edison Pettit Notebook 1935-1936 (Box 10)
  - Reports on research (Box 10)
  - Miscellanea regarding motion pictures, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Information concerning candidates for the chairmanship of the Department of Astronomy (Box 10)
  - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 10)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.
Nov. 9, 1940; Nov. 12, 1940; Feb. 4, 1941; Feb. 17, 1941; Oct. 3, 1941; Dec. 8, 1941; Dec. 13, 1941; Oct. 13, 1942; Nov. 4, 1942; May 14, 1943; May 20, 1943; Jan. 15, 1944; May 18, 1944; Aug. 7, 1944; Feb. 27, 1945; Apr. 7, 1946; Dec. 29, 1948; Apr. 19, 1943
Adams, Walter Sydney, 1876-1956.
Aug. 25, 1937; Nov. 30, 1937; Jan. 5, 1939; Apr. 12, 1939; Oct. 16, 1939; May 20, 1940; July-Dec. 1952; Jan.-Mar. 1954; Aug. 13, 1954; Aug. 20, 1954; Oct. 13, 1954; Nov. 2, 1954; Jan. 24, 1955; May 10, 1955; Nov. 1, 1955; Jan. 3, 1956
Adel, Arthur, 1908-
Nov. 3, 1947
Allen, Irwin, 1916-
In Jan.-June 1952 correspondence folder
Barker, Ernest Franklin, 1886-
Jan. 15, 1942
Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.
Dec. 20, 1937
Brown, Prentiss Marsh, 1889-1973
In July-Dec. 1952 correspondence folder
Burns, Kevin, 1881-1958.
Dec. 10, 1931; Nov. 5, 1932; Nov. 7, 1932; Aug. 7, 1936; Apr. 30, 1937; July 18, 1937; May 19, 1938; Jan. 10, 1939; Feb. 4, 1939; Feb. 15, 1939; Mar. 21, 1939; Apr. 10, 1939; June 22, 1939; May 13, 1940; Apr. 16, 1941; May 9, 1941; July 3, 1941; Nov. 20, 1941; Apr. 4, 1942
Burr, George Lindsley, 1889-
May 10, 1955; Apr. 18, 1956; Dec. 5, 1956
Bush, Vannevar, 1890-
May 11, 1938; June 17, 1938; Aug. 31, 1938; Jan. 3, 1939; Jan. 9, 1939; Mar. 18, 1939; Mar. 9, 1940; Mar. 15, 1940; Aug. 29, 1945, June 15, 1948
Cisler, Walker Lee, 1897-
Apr.-June 1954; July-Sept. 1954; Jan.-Mar. 1955; Mar.-Apr. 1958
May 1958; Oct.-Dec. 1960
Curtis, Heber Doust, 1872-1942.
Jan. 14, 1930; Jan. 31, 1930; Oct. 1930; Nov. 6, 1930; Nov. 11, 1930; Dec. 1, 1930; Jan. 1931; Mar. 1931; Apr. 1931; May 1931; Sept. 1931; Jan.-June 1932; Oct. 1932; Nov. 1932; Jan.-May 1933; July 1933; Sept.-Dec. 1933; Jan. - May 1934; July-Aug. 1934; Oct.-Dec. 1934; Jan. 1935; Apr.-Dec. 1935; 1936; Jan. 1927; May-Dec. 1937; Jan. 1938; Mar.-Dec. 1938; Jan.-June 1939; Oct.- Dec. 1939; 1940; Jan.-May 1941; Aug.-Dec. 1941
Curtiss, Ralph Hamilton, 1880-1929.
1928-1929
Dale, Albert Ennis, 1890-1954.
July 10, 1933
Davison, Frederick Trubee, 1896-
Apr. 27, 1938
Dodson, Helen Walter, 1905-
Throughout
Dodson, Helen Walter, 1905-
May 21, 1940; Apr. 1, 1949; July 29, 1957; May 28, 1960 and throughout
Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1893-1969.
July 2, 1954
Dunham, Theodore J. 1897-
Jan. 1946; May 1946; Dec. 2, 1949
Eckart, Carl, 1902-
Aug. 5, 1941; Aug. 11, 1941; Mar. 29, 1941
Edmondson, Frank K. (Frank Kelly), 1912-
Throughout AAS correspondence
Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.
Dec. 6, 1931
Fecker, J.W.
Mar.-June 1928; Jan.-May 1929; Oct.-Dec. 1930; Jan.-Feb. 1931; Sept. -Nov, 1931; Jan. 1932; Mar. 1932; July 1932; Sept.-Nov. 1932; Jan-1933; Feb. 28, 1933; Aug. 1934; Oct.-Dec. 1934, Mar. 1935, June-Oct- 1935, Dec. 1935; Jan.-Aug. 1936; July 1937
Fisher, Clyde, 1878-1949.
Jan. 2, 1936; Apr. 15, 1937; May 1, 1938; Dec. 18, 1940; Apr. 16, 1941
Gardner, Erle Stanley, 1889-1970.
Jan. 6, 1951
Gilmore, William Steele, 1884-
Sept. 21, 1936
Goldberg, Leo, 1913-
Feb. 17, 1942; Oct. 2, 1942; Oct. 15, 1942; Nov. 4, 1942; Nov 17, 1942; Nov. 25, 1942; Jan. 25, 1943; Jan. 28, 1943; Feb.-Mar. 1943; Oct. 14, 1943; Nov. 25, 1943; Dec. 13, 1943; Jan. 1944; Aug. 3, 1944; Jan. 6, 1945; Jan. 13, 1945; Jan. 17, 1945; Jan. 25, 1945; Apr. 30, 1945; Aug. 28, 1945; Nov. 17, 1945; Dec. 1, 1945; Jan. 2, 1946; Jan. 29, 1946; Feb.-June 1946; Sept. 1946; July-Aug. 1947; Mar. 1948; May-July 1948; Dec. 1948; Feb. 1949; May 1949; Jan.-June 1950; Nov. 1950; May 1951; Nov. 1951; Jan.-June 1952; Aug. 1954; Dec. 10, 1958
Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966.
Mar. 19, 1937; Apr. 22, 1937; May 26, 1939; Feb. 7, 1941; Oct. 24, 1949
Grosvenor, Melville Bell, 1901-1982.
Dec. 17, 1937; Jan. 17, 1938
Heyns, Roger William,1918-
Dec. 10, 1958
Hulbert, Henry Schoolcraft, 1869-1959.
Jan. 14, 1930; Jan. 15, 1930; Jan. 20, 1930; Feb. 7, 1930, Feb. 8, 1930; Feb. 27, 1930; Mar. 19, 1930; Apr. 11, 1930; Apr. 18, 1930; May 26, 1930; June 12, 1930; May 11, 1930; Aug 6, 1932; Dec. 14, 1932; Mar. 9, 1933; Mar. 24, 1933; Mar. 3, 1934; June 3, 1936; Jan. 18, 1937; Feb. 18, 1937; May 19 1937; July 13, 1937; July 16, 1937; Nov. 12, 1937; Jan. 7, 1939; Apr. 18, 1939; Oct. 14, 1939; Jan. 3, 1940; Feb. 9, 1940; May 2, 1940; Oct. 10, 1940; Feb. 15, 1941; July 1, 1941; Jan. 24, 1942; Apr. 2, 1942; June 4, 1942; June 11, 1942; July 18, 1942; Jan 23 1942, July 4, 1943; Dec. 27, 1943; May 10, 1944; May 9, 1947; May 5, 19, 1948
Johnson, Nelson C.
June 12, 1944, Aug. 1, 1944, Aug. 5, 1944
Karpinski, Louis Charles.1878-1956.
Mar. 21, 1943, June 9, 1943
Keller, Kaufman Thuma, 1885-1966.
Jan.-June 1953 folder; July-Dec. 1953 folder
Kellogg, Remington, 1892-
July 16 1948
Keniston, Hayward, 1883-
Nov. 8, 1945
Klopsteg, Paul E. (Paul Ernest), 1889-
1949-1954 throughout
Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-
Jan. 22, 1942; Jan. 26, 1942; June 10, 1942; June 16, 1942; June 21, 1944
Learer, F. H.
Feb. 20, 1937; Mar. 21, 1937; Apr. 12, 1937; May 11, 1937; June 12, 1937; June 14, 1937; July 13, 1937; July 26, 1937; July 27, 1937; Aug. 8, 1937; Aug. 24, 1937; Aug. 27, 1937; Sept. 15, 1937; Nov. 30, 1937; Dec 23, 1937; June 23, 1938; July 6, 1938
McClure, Roy Donaldson, 1882-1951.
July 1939; Jan. 1940; Mar. 24; 1941; Apr. 8, 1941; Apr. 15, 1941; Apr. 19, 1941; Nov. 25, 1941
McDowell, C. S.
July 16, 1935; Oct. 15, 1935; Nov. 14, 1935; July 1, 1936; July 15, 1936; Oct. 30, 1936; July 3, 1937; Oct. 8, 1937;Dec. 3, 1937; Dec. 13, 1937; Jan. 25, 1938; Mar. 26, 1936; Apr. 2, 1938; May 9, 1938; May 10, 1938; May 19, 1938; May 27, 1938; June 11, 1938; June 22, 1938; Sept. 11, 1938; Sept. 24, 1938; Oct. 3, 1938; Apr. 23, 1947
McGregor, Tracy William, 1869-1936.
Dec. 26, 1933; Mar. 22, 1934; May 7, 1934; June 22, 1934; Sept 12, 1934; Nov. 23, 1934; Dec. 7, 1934; Apr. 19, 1935; Jan. 20, 1936; Apr. 2, 1936
McMath, Francis Charles, 1867-1938.
Nov. 28, 1930; Jan. 1931; May 1931; May 1, 1933; May 24, 1933; Oct. 22, 1935, Nov. 21, 1935; Dec. 2, 1935; Dec. 6, 1935; Dec. 21, 1936, May 19, 1937; May 28, 1937; June 1, 1937; Sept. 21, 1937
Malesky, George.
May 19, 1939; July 19, 1939; Sept. 25, 1939; Nov. 17, 1939, Mar. 27, 1940; Feb. 17, 1943; Feb. 20, 1943; Mar.-Apr. 1943; Apr. 3, 1944; June 22, 1944; June 28, 1944, July 5, 1944; July 6, 1944; Aug. 17, 1944; Oct. 8, 1944; Nov. 3, 1944
Menzel, Donald Howard, 1901-
Sept. 29, 1937; Mar. 15, 1938; Apr. 10, 1938; Apr. 29, 1938; Jan. 18, 1939; Mar. 3, 1939; Mar. 24, 1939; Mar. 29, 1939; May 9, 1939; July 21, 1939; Mar. 13, 1940; May 24, 1940; July 18, 1940; July 31, 1940; Aug. 23 1940; Sept. 24, 1940; Oct. 21, 1940; Nov. 29, 1940; Dec. 23, 1940; Jan. 15, 1941; Feb. 14, 1941; Feb. 28, 1941, Mar. 24, 1941; Aug. 18, 1941; Aug. 26, 1941; Nov. 12, 1941; Nov. 25, 1941; Dec. 8, 1941; Mar. 2, 1942; May 5, 1942; July 4, 1942; Aug. 15, 1942; Aug. 22, 1942; Dec. 22, 1943; Dec. 21, 1943; May 20, 1944; Oct. 27, 1945; Aug. 22, 1946; Aug. 27, 1946; Nov. 22, 1946; Throughout AAS correspondence
Merrill, Paul W. (Paul Willard), 1887-
July 18, 1937; July 19, 1937
Mohler, Orren, 1908-
Oct. 25, 1933; Feb. 12, 1934; July 30, 1934; Mar. 31, 1939; Sept. 13, 1939; Sept. 14, 1939; Oct. 7, 1939; Mar. 29, 1941; May 27, 1941; Aug. 25, 1941; June 17, 1941; Aug. 15, 1941; Oct. 6, 1941; Oct. 9, 1941; Oct. 13, 1941; Nov. 7, 1941; Feb. 2, 1942; Feb. 10, 1942; Mar. 17, 1942; Mar. 18, 1942; Mar. 25, 1942; May 27, 1942; June 16, 1942; June 28, 1942; July 25, 1942; Aug. 1, 1942; Aug. 3, 1942; Aug. 5, 1942; Sept.-Oct. 1942; Dec. 8, 1942; Dec. 15, 1942; Jan. 13, 1943; Mar. 1943; June 23, 1943; Aug. 9, 1943; Oct. 16, 1943; Oct. 21, 1943; Oct. 22, 1943; Nov. 1, 1943; Dec. 30, 1943; Jan. 12, 1944; Jan. 31, 1944; Mar. 30, 1944; Apr. 7, 1944; May 12, 1944; July 11, 1944; Aug. 7, 1944; Sept. 15, 1944; Sept. 28, 1944; Nov. 27, 1944; July 30, 1945; July 31, 1945; Nov. 7, 1945; Nov. 8, 1945; Nov. 19, 1945; Dec. 6, 1945; Jan. 30, 1946; Mar. 8, 1946; June 7, 1946; Aug.-Oct. 1946; Jan.-May 1947; Sept.-Nov. 1947; Nov. 1948; Jan. 1949; July 1949; May 28, 1960
Nicholson, Seth Barnes, 1891-
Oct. 31, 1936; Mar. 10, 1939; May 10, 1939; Feb. 5, 1943, Feb. 15, 1943
Norton, William J. (William John), 1883-1975.
Aug. 1, 1941; Aug. 8, 1941; Aug. 15, 1941; Aug. 22, 1941; Aug. 29, 1941; Sept. 5, 1941; Sept. 12, 1941; Sept. 25, 1941; Oct. 3, 1941; Oct. 10, 1941; Oct. 22, 1941; Jan. 26, 1942; May 10, 1954
Odegaard, Charles E.
May 24, 1956; Dec. 6, 1956
Ormondroyd, J. (Jesse), 1897-
Oct. 5, 1939, Sept. 28, 1959
Petrie, Robert Methven, 1906-
May 17, 1933; Dec. 21, 1933; Apr. 28, 1937; Aug. 2, 1937; Nov. 7, 1937; Nov. 7, 1937; Feb. 5, 1938; Oct. 18, 1938; Jan. 9, 1939; Mar. 8, 1940; Mar. 27, 1940; Apr. 16?, 1940; May 30, 1940; Nov. 25, 1940; Sept. 14, 1941; Dec. 17, 1941; Dec. 31, 1941; Feb. 17, 1942; Jan. 22, 1946; July 11, 1959
Pettit, Edison, 1889-1962.
Oct. 11, 1934; Nov. 5, 1933; Jan 24, 1935; Feb. 26, 1935; Mar. 14, 1935; May 27, 1935; June 2, 1935; Aug. 4, 1935; Aug. 25, 1935; Oct. 15, 1935; Nov. 2, 1935; Nov. 25, 1935; Feb. 2, 1936; Feb. 21, 1936; Mar.-June 1936; Sept.-Dec. 1936; Jan.-Apr. 1937; Sept. 17, 1937; Sept. 19, 1937; Oct.-Dec. 1937; Jan.-May 1938; Sept.-Nov. 1938; Dec. 27, 1938; Jan. 1939; Mar.-June 1939
Pyke, Alfred Joseph.
Feb, 26, 1940; Feb. 1942; Aug. 23, 1942; Sept. 12, 1942; Oct. 23 1942; Oct. 28, 1942
Quarles, Donald Aubrey, 1894-1959.
Dec. 28, 1954
Reynolds, Harrison G.
Aug. 17, 1954
Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1899-
Oct. 2, 1943; Oct. 13, 1943; Nov. 12, 1945; Nov. 16.1945; Sept. 25, 1947
Russell, Henry Norris, 1877-1957.
Jan. 4, 1939; Jan. 10, 1939; May 19, 1947; June 3, 1947; Oct. 17, 1947; Nov. 4, 1947; Apr. 9, 1948
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-
Apr. 24, 1930; Apr. 29, 1930; Feb. 14, 1931; Sept. 4, 1931; Sept. 26, 1931; Nov. 3, 1931; Dec. 29, 1931; Feb. 1932; Oct. 25, 1932; Apr. 4,1933; Apr. 8, 1933; June 23, 1933; Feb. 10, 1934; Nov. 3, 1934; Dec. 9, 1934; Mar. 14, 1935; Apr. 30, 1935; Nov. 8, 1935; Oct. 2, 1936; Nov. 9, 1936; Dec. 26, 1936; Mar. 1, 1937; Mar. 4, 1937; Mar. 16, 1937; Apr. 7, 1937; May 4, 1937; June 25, 1937; July 3, 1937; Sept. 29, 1937; Feb. 2, 1939; Aug. 3, 1939; Nov. 14, 1939; Dec. 9, 1939; Mar. 4, 1940; May 27, 1940; Oct. 2, 1940; Jan. 21, 1941; Jan. 23, 1941; Apr. 10, 1941; Nov. 10, 1941; Dec. 17, 1941; Dec. 26., 1941; Jan. 17, 1942; March 5, 1942; Feb. 28, 1945; May 28, 1948
Sass, Samuel, 1915-
Oct. 23, 1942; Oct. 29, 1942; Nov. 7, 1942; Nov. 13, 1942; Dec. 2, 1942; Dec. 7, 1942; Feb. 15, 1943; Feb. 18, 1943; Mar. 25 1943; Nov. 24 1943; Jan. 7, 1944; Jan 10 1944; Apr. 7, 1944; May 1, 1944; May 4, 1944; July 22, 1944; Oct. 22, 1944; Nov. 18, 1944; Jan. 15, 1951
Sawyer, H. E.
Feb. 21, 1942; Dec. 31, 1946; June 27, 1955
Schauer, Charles Hawver, 1912-
May 18, 1948; June 7, 1948; June 17, 1948; June 18, 1948; Oct. 14, 1948; Oct. 20, 1948; Dec. 10, 1948; Feb. 23, 1949; Dec. 6, 1949
Schriever, Bernard A.